myhome.com.au 2015-11-27

# Real Estate Australia on realestateview.com.au - Australian property listings

## realestateVIEW.com.au Limited

### We respect your privacy

realestateview.com.au Limited ( **we** , **us** , **our** ) recognise the importance of protecting the privacy and the rights of individuals in relation to their personal information. This document is our privacy policy and it tells you how we collect and manage your personal information.

Whenever we collect, handle, store, use or disclose personal information that you provide to us when using this site or via e-mail, we comply with the requirements contained in the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth), including the Australian Privacy Principles.

### What is personal information?

Personal information is any information (whether fact, opinion or evaluative material) about you as an individual, from which your identity is apparent or can reasonably be ascertained. This includes your name, address, telephone number, email address and profession or occupation. If the information we collect personally identifies you, or you are reasonably identifiable from it, the information will be considered personal information. The following statement sets out:

  * our policies on the management of personal information; and
  * what sort of personal information we hold, for what purposes and how we collect, hold, use and disclose that information.

### What personal information do we collect and hold?

We may collect the following types of personal information:

  * name;
  * mailing or street address;
  * email address;
  * telephone number;
  * facsimile number;
  * age or birth date;
  * profession, occupation or job title;
  * details of the services you have acquired from us or which you have enquired about, together with any additional information necessary to deliver those services and to respond to your enquiries; and
  * any additional information relating to you that you provide to us directly through our website or indirectly through use of our website or online presence or otherwise.

We also collect some information that is not personal information because it does not identify you or anyone else. For example, we may collect anonymous answers to surveys or aggregated information about how users use our website.

### For what purposes do we collect personal information?

We only collect personal information about you for the purpose of delivering and improving the site and the services we provide and to enhance and develop our relationship with you, as well as personalising our offering and establishing accounts.

Generally, those services relate to advertising real estate and businesses, and any other services such as finance, conveyancing, removalist services, property maintenance and any other related real estate service.

### When do we collect personal information?

Where possible, we will collect your personal information that you provide directly to us. Generally, we collect personal information about you in the following situations:

  * you register as a site user or establish an account;
  * you send us an e-mail;
  * you post a message to our message board;
  * you give us personal information when using any part of the web site, such as the chat rooms, billboards and pagebuilder sites; and
  * you use our services.

We will only collect information that is related to the services that you ask us to provide to you.

We also collect personal information from third parties including:

  * from third party companies such as credit reporting bodies, law enforcement agencies and other government entities;
  * from any third party that refers you to us, or referred your listing to us; and
  * from other service providers and businesses that we have partnered with to provide a product or service, including in relation to a co-branded, jointly branded, or “white label” product”.

### What happens if we can’t collect your personal information?

If you do not provide us with the personal information described above, some or all of the following may happen:

  * we may not be able to provide the requested services to you, either to the same standard or at all;
  * we may not be able to open an account for you, or provide you with any personalised services;
  * we may not be able to provide you with information about the services that you may want, including information about discounts, sales or special promotions; or
  * we may be unable to tailor the content of our website to your preferences and your experience of our website may not be as enjoyable or useful.

### We track usage patterns for our site

When you visit this site, our server logs the following information provided by your browser:

  * the type of browser and operating system you are using;
  * the previous site that you visited;
  * your server's IP address (a number which is unique to the machine through which you are connected to the Internet - usually one of your service provider's machines);
  * the date and time of your visit;
  * the address of the pages accessed; and
  * the documents downloaded.

We only use the information logged by our server for the purpose of statistical usage analysis or systems administration.

### Cookies, web beacons

We use a feature of your browser called a 'cookie' to assign a user ID. Cookies identify your computer to our servers when you visit our site. You need to have configured your browser to enable the accepting or sending of cookies in order to use the full functionality of this site. Cookies from third parties, for example banner ads, may also be used, depending on the policies of the third party suppliers of banner ads and other site add-ons. If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, you may be able to change the settings of your browser to refuse all cookies or to notify you each time a cookie is sent to your computer, giving you the choice whether to accept it or not. Like many websites, our website may also use web beacons (also known as pixel tags, spotlight tags or web bugs) to improve our understanding of site traffic, visitor behaviour, and to respond to promotional campaigns. These are a supplement to our server logs and other methods of traffic and response measurement. We may also implement pixel tags provided by other companies, for the same purpose. Information collected through the use of web beacons on our website is not linked to personal information.

### Online Behavioural Advertising

Telstra’s digital advertising network is responsible for placing some of the advertising on this site. To make this advertising more relevant to you, anonymous information about the previous web browsing activity of your computer on sites within Telstra’s network is collected and used to associate your computer with one or more pre-defined interest categories. Advertising that matches those interest categories may then be served to your computer. This interest based advertising does not change the amount of advertising you receive, it just makes it more relevant. You can learn more about the interest based advertising conducted by Telstra here. General information about interest based advertising is available from the industry website [www.youronlinechoices.com.au](http://www.youronlinechoices.com.au/), and you can also opt out of some or all interest based advertising here.

### Search terms

Search terms that you enter when searching our publications database engine are collected, but are not associated with any other information that we collect. We use these search terms to ascertain what people are looking for at our site, and to improve the services that we provide.

### Disclosure of information to others accessing the site

Any person who is a user of our site may access, download and print any information you provide to our chat rooms, billboards and pagebuilder sites. By accessing any of our billboards, pagebuilder sites or like services, you consent to the disclosure of any personal information you provide while participating in any of these services to any other person participating in any of these services, whether at the time you are participating or at a later time. We are not responsible for the use or disclosure by others of the information you provide to our site.

### If you send us an e-mail

If you send us an e-mail containing personal information we take steps to ensure the confidentiality of that information. The content of e-mails is sometimes monitored for maintenance and fault detection purposes or for legal compliance purposes. We may use your e-mail address for the purpose for which you provided it. We may also use your e-mail address to respond to feedback given about this site, and to confirm receipt of e-mails if we need to contact you for any reason. We may send you an e-mail providing general information about services that we provide or that are available to you from other persons, to provide any information you request. Each time we do that, we will give you the opportunity to choose not to receive more e-mails of that type.

### For what purposes do we collect, hold, use and disclose your personal information?

We collect personal information about you so that we can perform our business activities and functions and to provide best possible quality of customer service.

We collect, hold, use and disclose your personal information for the following purposes:

  * to provide products and services to you and to send communications requested by you;
  * to answer enquiries and provide information or advice about existing and new products or services;
  * to tailor our service and deliver a personalised offering;
  * to provide you with access to protected areas of our website;
  * to assess the performance of the website and to improve the operation of the website;
  * to conduct business processing functions including providing personal information to our related bodies corporate, contractors, service providers or other third parties;
  * for the administrative, marketing (including direct marketing), planning, product or service development, quality control and research purposes of Australian real estate institutes, as well as us and our related bodies corporate, contractors or service providers;
  * to provide your updated personal information to our related bodies corporate, contractors or service providers;
  * to enable third party providers to provide services in connection with our business, such as Houseandland.com.au Pty Ltd, which provides a searching functionality product on our website;
  * to update our records and keep your contact details up to date;
  * to process and respond to any complaint made by you; and
  * to comply with any law, rule, regulation, lawful and binding determination, decision or direction of a regulator, or in co-operation with any governmental authority of any country.

Your personal information will not be shared, sold, rented or disclosed other than as described in this Privacy Policy.

### Do we disclose personal information to anyone else?

It is generally our policy not to disclose information to external organisations, however, we may sometimes need to disclose your personal information to others for the purposes set out above. Examples of the types of organisations we may wish to disclose information to for these purposes are:

  * our related bodies corporate;
  * Australian real estate institutes;
  * parties outside realestateview.com.au Ltd who are contracted to us to provide a particular service on our behalf, such as: mailing houses for bulk mailing of letters and notices; printers for marketing material; parties that provide functionality on our website, or other products and services via our website; and other service providers;
  * parties that we share listings with, such as other websites that list properties for sale and lease; and
  * with your express consent, any organisation for any authorised purpose.

Those contracted parties are not authorised by us to use personal information for anything other than the purpose for which we supplied that information to them. Sometimes the law requires us to disclose personal information. For example, information may be disclosed to a court in response to a subpoena or to a Government agency.

### Do we disclose your personal information to anyone outside Australia?

We may disclose personal information to our related bodies corporate and third party suppliers and service providers located overseas for some of the purposes listed above, but do not do so currently. If we commence to disclose your personal information to parties outside of Australia, we will take reasonable steps to ensure that the overseas recipients of your personal information do not breach the privacy obligations relating to your personal information.

### Direct marketing

From time to time we may use your personal information to inform you about our services and products or promotions that we think may be of interest to you. These communications are sent in various forms, including mail, SMS, fax and email, in accordance with applicable marketing laws, such as the Spam Act 2003 (Cth). You consent to us sending you those direct marketing communications by any of those methods. If you indicate a preference for a method of communication, we will endeavour to use that method whenever practical to do so. In addition, at any time you may opt-out of receiving marketing communications from us by contacting us (see the details below) or by using opt-out facilities provided in the marketing communications and we will then ensure that your name is removed from our mailing list.

If the law requires us to provide you with information about our products or services, we will provide that information even if you have elected not to receive information about those products or services generally.

We do not currently, but may in future, provide your personal information to other organisations for the purposes of direct marketing. If we do so, your details would only be provided to suppliers that have a relationship with us, in relation to goods or services that you have indicated may be of interest to you.

### Security of personal information

Security of personal information is important to us and we take all reasonable precautions to protect personal information for misuse, loss, unauthorised access, modification or disclosure. Some of the ways we protect personal information include:

  * external and internal premises security;
  * restricting access to personal information only to staff who need it to perform their day to day functions;
  * maintaining technology products to prevent unauthorised computer access or damage to electronically stored information, such as requiring identifiers and passwords, firewalls and anti-virus software; and
  * maintaining physical security over paper records.

We may hold your information in either electronic or hard copy form. Personal information is destroyed or de-identified when no longer needed.

The internet is not a secure environment. If you use the internet to send us any information, including your email address, it is sent at your own risk.

### We will correct inaccurate information

We rely on the personal information we hold in conducting our business. Therefore, it is very important that the information we hold is accurate, complete and up-to-date. We do everything we can to ensure that the personal information we hold is accurate, complete and up-to-date whenever we collect or use it. This means that from time to time, we will ask you to tell us if there are any changes to your personal information. If any of the information we are holding is inaccurate, incomplete or out of date and we become aware of this, we will take reasonable steps to correct the information so that it is accurate, complete and up-to-date.

If you believe that personal information we hold about you is incorrect, incomplete or inaccurate, then you have the right to request us to amend it. We will consider if the information requires amendment. If we do not agree that there are grounds for amendment then we will add a note to the personal information stating that you disagree with it.

### You can access personal information we hold about you

You have the right to request access to any personal information we hold about you at any time by contacting us (see the details below). Where we hold information that you are entitled to access, we will try to provide you with suitable means of accessing it (for example, by mailing or emailing it to you). If any of the information we are holding is inaccurate, we will correct it for you if you request that we do so. We will not charge you for making a request for access. However, we may charge you for the reasonable administrative costs that we incur in providing access to this information. We will notify you of these costs at the time you request access to your personal information.

There may be instances where we cannot grant you access to the personal information we hold. For example, we may need to refuse access if granting access would interfere with the privacy of others or if it would result in a breach of confidentiality. If that happens, we will give you written reasons for any refusal.

### Third party web sites

This site contains links to other sites which are owned or operated by third parties independent of us. Those owners or operators are responsible for informing you about their security and privacy practices. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any sites linked to our site. Therefore, prior to disclosing your personal information on any other website, we recommend that you review the terms and conditions of use for that website and its privacy statement.

### What is the process for complaining about a breach of privacy?

If you believe that your privacy has been breached (by us or our contractors), please contact our Privacy Officer as a first point of call using the contact information below and provide details of the incident so that we can investigate it.

We request that complaints about breaches of privacy be made in writing, so we can be sure about the details of the complaint. Our Privacy Officer deals with privacy complaints and any complaints should be directed to our Privacy Officer using the contact details below. We will attempt to confirm as appropriate and necessary with you your understanding of the conduct relevant to the complaint and what you expect as an outcome. We will inform you within 30 days whether we will conduct an investigation, the name, title, and contact details of the investigating officer and the estimated completion date for the investigation process.

After we have completed our enquiries, we will contact you, usually in writing, to advise the outcome and invite a response to our conclusions about the complaint. If we receive a response from you, we will assess it and advise if we have changed our view. If you are unhappy with the outcome and our further response, you have the right to lay a complaint with the Privacy Commissioner.

### Contact details

If you have any questions about this privacy policy, the practices of this site or your dealings with this site, you should contact our Privacy Officer using the details set out below.

We will treat your requests or complaints confidentially. Our representative will contact you within a reasonable time after receipt of your complaint to discuss your concerns and outline options regarding how they may be resolved. We will aim to ensure that your complaint is resolved in timely and appropriate manner.

Please contact our Privacy Officer at:

The Privacy Officer  
realestateview.com.au Ltd  
Post: 335 Camberwell Road, Camberwell, Victoria 3124  
Tel: +61 3 9205 6623  
Email: psprekos@realestateview.com.au  

### Changes to our privacy policy

We may change this privacy policy from time to time. Any updated versions of this privacy policy will be posted on our website. Please review it regularly.

This privacy policy was last updated on 7 May 2015.
